universal-robots.com 2019-12-30

# Universal Robots A/S Privacy Policy

Universal Robots A/S Privacy Policy
Universal Robots A/S ("Universal Robots") takes processing of your personal data very seriously. We
ensure a reasonable and transparent processing in accordance with the rules on processing of
personal data, including the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR").
This Privacy Policy applies for the Personal Data Universal Robots collects about individuals,
customers, suppliers (including third party service providers), other stakeholders and Users of the
Website. Although information regarding companies/businesses is not as such Personal Data,
however information relating to contacts within such businesses, e.g. name, title, work email, work
phone number, etc. is considered personal data.
Owner and Data Controller
Universal Robots is the owner and data controller in regard to the personal data we have received
from you and any reference to “Owner” herein shall mean Universal Robots.
We can be contacted via the following information:
Universal Robots A/S
CVR-number: 29138060
Energivej 25, 5260 Odense S, Denmark
Contact email: marketing@universal-robots.com
Contact telephone number: +45 89 93 89 89
Types of Data collected
Among the types of Personal Data that Universal Robots collects, by itself or through third parties,
there are: Cookies, Usage Data, first name, phone number, other contact details, company name, title,
country, various types of Data, city, number of employees and email address.
Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected regarding Users are provided in the
dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data
collection. Personal Data may be freely provided by you, in case of Usage Data, collected
automatically when using this Website.
Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by this Website is mandatory and failure to provide this
Data may make it impossible for this Website to provide its services. In cases where this Website
specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data
without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service. Users who are uncertain
about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Website or by the owners of third-party
services used by this Website serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in
addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if
available.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through this
Website and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner.
Methods of processing
The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure,
modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data. The Data processing is carried out using
computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to
the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain
types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of this Website (administration, sales,
marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service
providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if
necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from
the Owner at any time.
The Purpose of processing
The Data concerning you is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Services, necessary for
conducting business including enter into agreements, as well as in some cases for the following
purposes: Analytics, Contacting, managing contacts and sending messages, Remarketing and
behavioral targeting and Advertising. You can find further detailed information about such purposes
of processing and about the specific Personal Data used for each purpose in the respective sections of
this document.
Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data when you are a User
Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:
     •  Advertising
     •  Analytics
     •  Contacting the User
     •  Managing contacts and sending messages
     •  Remarketing and behavioral targeting
Legal basis of processing
The Owner may process Personal Data if one of the following applies:
       You have given your consent for one or more specific purposes. Note: Under some legislations
        the Owner may be allowed to process Personal Data until you object to such processing (“opt-
        out”), without having to rely on consent or any other of the following legal bases. This,
        however, does not apply, whenever the processing of Personal Data is subject to European
        data protection law;
       provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with you and/or for any
        pre-contractual obligations thereof;
       processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;
       processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of
        official authority vested in the Owner;
                                                                                                   Page 2 of 6

        processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or
         by a third party.
In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing,
and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a
requirement necessary to enter into a contract.
Place
The Data is processed at the Owner's operating offices and in any other places where the parties
involved in the processing are located.
Depending on your location, data transfers may involve transferring your Data to a country other than
your own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check
the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.
If broader protection standards are applicable, you are also entitled to learn about the legal basis of
Data transfers to a country outside the European Union (“EU”) or to any international organization
governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about
the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard your Data.
If any such transfer takes place, you can find out more by checking the relevant sections of this
document or inquire with the Owner using the information provided in the contact section.
Retention time
Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been
collected for. Therefore:
        Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract shall be
         retained until such contract has been fully performed.
        Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained
         as long as needed to fulfil such purposes. You may find specific information regarding the
         legitimate interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by
         contacting the Owner.
The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever you have given
consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be
obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to do so for the performance of
a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.
Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right to access, the
right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after
expiration of the retention period.
                                                                                                   Page 3 of 6

The purposes of processing
The Data concerning you is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, necessary for
conducting business including enter into agreements, as well as in some cases for the following
purposes: Analytics, Contacting, managing contacts and sending messages, Remarketing and
behavioural targeting and Advertising.
You can find further detailed information about such purposes of processing and about the specific
Personal Data used for each purpose in the respective sections of this document.
Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data when you are a User
Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:
        Advertising
        Analytics
        Contacting the User
        Managing contacts and sending messages
        Remarketing and behavioural targeting
Your rights
You may exercise certain rights regarding your Data processed by the Owner.
If you are a User, you may be entitled to broader protection standards may exercise any of the rights
described below. In all other cases, Users may inquire with the Owner to find out which rights apply to
them.
In particular, you have the right to do the following:
        Withdraw your consent at any time. You have the right to withdraw consent where you have
         previously given your consent to the processing of your Personal Data.
        Object to processing of your Data. You have the right to object to the processing of your Data
         if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent. Further details are provided
         in the dedicated section below.
        Access your Data. You have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain
         disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data
         undergoing processing.
        Verify and seek rectification. You have the right to verify the accuracy of your Data and ask
         for it to be updated or corrected.
        Restrict the processing of your Data. You have the right, under certain circumstances, to
         restrict the processing of your Data. In this case, the Owner will not process your Data for any
         purpose other than storing it.
        Have your Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed. You have the right, under certain
         circumstances, to obtain the erasure of your Data from the Owner.
        Receive your Data and have it transferred to another controller. You have the right to receive
         your Data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and, if technically
         feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance. This provision is
                                                                                                  Page 4 of 6

         applicable provided that the Data is processed by automated means and that the processing is
         based on your consent, on a contract which you or your company is part of or on pre-
         contractual obligations thereof.
        Lodge a complaint. You have the right to bring a claim before your competent data protection
         authority.
Details about the right to object to processing
Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in
the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, you may object to
such processing by providing a ground related to your particular situation to justify the objection.
You must know that, however, should your Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes,
you can object to that processing at any time without providing any justification. To learn, whether
the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, you may refer to the relevant
sections of this document.
How to exercise these rights
Any requests to exercise your rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details
provided in this Privacy Policy. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed
by the Owner as early as possible and always within one (1) month.
Applicability of broader protection standards regarding some Users
While most provisions of this document concern all Users, some provisions expressly only apply if the
processing of Personal Data is subject to broader protection standards.
Such broader protection standards apply when the processing:
        is performed by an Owner based within the EU;
        concerns the Personal Data of Users who are in the EU and is related to the offering of paid or
         unpaid goods or services, to such Users;
        concerns the Personal Data of Users who are in the EU and allows the Owner to monitor such
         Users’ behaviour taking place in the EU.
Cookie Policy
Universal Robots, as the Owner, uses cookies on some portions of its Websites. A cookie is an
identifier that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer. Cookies enable
us to provide you with a better experience by allowing us to understand what areas of our Website
are of interest to our visitors. The Owner may also use cookies when you register to use one of our
web-based services. In this situation, a cookie will store useful information that enables our Web site
to remember you when you return to visit us. The Owner can only read cookies from the Owner’s
Websites. If you choose to disable cookies in your browser, you can still access most of our Websites.
This Website uses Cookies. To learn more and for a detailed cookie notice, you may consult Universal
Robots’ Cookie Policy which can be located at the front page of our Website or at via the following
url: https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/75145020/cookie-policy.
                                                                                                Page 5 of 6

Additional information about Data collection and processing
Legal action
Your Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to
possible legal action. You are hereby made aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal
data upon request of public authorities.
Additional information about your Personal Data
In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, our Website may provide you with
additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing
of Personal Data upon request.
System logs and maintenance
For operation and maintenance purposes, our Website and any third-party services may collect files
that record interaction with this Website (System logs) use other Personal Data (such as the IP
Address) for this purpose.
Information not contained in this policy
More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the
Owner at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.
How “Do Not Track” requests are handled
Our Website does not support “Do Not Track” requests. To determine whether any of the third-party
services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.
Changes to this privacy policy
The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to you
on this page and possibly within our Website and/or - as far as technically and legally feasible -
sending a notice to you via any contact information available to the Owner. It is strongly
recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the
bottom.
Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of your consent, the Owner
shall collect new consent from you, where required.
                                                                                                Page 6 of 6
